# SANDIP **THAPA**

Tinthana-14, Chandragiri, Bagmati Province, Nepal sandipthapa386@gmail.com (+977) 9808976977

A highly motivated and hard-working individual, graduate of Computer Science with 3 years of active participation on software development. Wide range of technical skill-set and attention to detail. Loves to work in an environment where I could create digital magic and elevate user interface and experience to the next level.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**NOV 2023 - PRESENT** 

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ASTERDIO INC.**

- Define the overall structure and architecture of the software system.
- Design software solutions that meet specified requirements.
- Write, test, and maintain code for software applications.
- Identify and fix bugs and errors in the code.
- Work closely with other team members, including product managers, designers, and other developers.
- Create and maintain technical documentation for software systems.

**JAN 2022 - OCT 2023** 

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CAGTU NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- Convert Figma designs into web pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop new user-facing features using React.js and Next.js with Typescript.
- Develop and maintain fast, bug-free, and re-usable components for the in-house product.
- Collaborate with design team to enhance user interfaces and its experience.
- Implement and manage version controlling of the project using git flow.

**SEPT 2021 - DEC 2021** 

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, EKBANA SOLUTIONS PTE. LTD.

- Developed supermarket app with React.js.
- API integration and data handling using Context API.
- Got to learn about Software Development Life Cycle using SCRUM.

# **EDUCATION**

2018 - 2021

BSc (Hons) IT, HERALD COLLEGE, UNIVERSITY OF WOLVERHAMPTON

- Introduced to fundamentals of programming, Data Structure & Algorithms & DBMS.
- Assigned to multiple mini and group projects.
- Worked on different research, communication and collaboration skills.

2016 - 2018

INTERMEDIATE - SCIENCE, KATHMANDU BERNHARDT COLLEGE

Majors: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

### **PROJECTS**

**MAR 2024 - PRESENT** 

**Auctions by Auto24**, Vehicles Auction Platform

Technologies: Next.js(SSG, ISR), Typescript, SCSS, Docker

View Project 2

**JAN 2024 - PRESENT** 

Auto24 - Automobiles Dealership System

Technologies: React.js, Ant Design, Redux

View Project ☐

**NOV 2023 - JAN 2024** 

Mero Moto - Vehicle Buy/Sale Platform

Technologies: Next.js(SSR), Typescript, Ant Design, Node.js

View Project 2

# **KEY SKILLS**

HTML5

- CSS3/SCSS/Tailwind CSS Bootstrap5
- Javascript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- React Query
- Mantine UI
- Ant Design Formik

SCRUM

Communication

Critical Thinking

Team Work

Leadership

- Yup
- Gitlab
- Git
- Docker Figma

## **SOCIAL ACCOUNTS**

https://www.sandipthapa.com.np/ Portfolio:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandipthapa99/ LinkedIn:

https://github.com/sandipthapa99/ • Github: